Guide to the Marcel Kurpershoek Papers AD.MC.054
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Publications, circa 1988-2020
  - Other writings: Library of Arabic Literature (NYU Abu Dhabi)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Source materials (photocopied): stories about al-Dhahir, compiled by Sultan Alameemi (al- 'Amīmī) (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Transcriptions with edits, Arabic stories (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Transcriptions with edits, Poems 1-16 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, speeches, and miscellaneous writings, 1970-2020
  - Biographical: news clippings and magazine articles about Kurpershoek, 2000-2021 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Book publication, general, 2000, and undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Lemhuis, Fred, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Research, general, 1989-2000 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Research trips, planning and logistics, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Research trips, planning and logistics, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Research trips: Al-Blehid, Sheikh 'Abdallah ibn Mohammed (Deputy Governor, Province of Riyadh), 1994 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Saudi Arabia, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Sowayyan, Saad, 1990-2000 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Sultan, Madiha (Radio Nederland), regarding interview about Yusuf Idris, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Udink, Betsy (wife): letters sent to her by M. Kurpershoek from Saudi Arabia, during his fieldwork, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Zayed Centre for Coordination (Abu Dhabi), regarding lectures given by Kurpershoek, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Readings of Bedouin poetry (used in lectures, radio broadcasts): Arabic texts (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Readings of Bedouin poetry (used in lectures, radio broadcasts): Dutch translations and notes (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Research trips, planning and receipts, 1996-1998 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Writings: "Palestijnse Dichter strijdt met het Vers," unattributed article in "Het Vaderland", 28 March 1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Writings: "Sadat voelt zich niet veilig...", written under pseudonym, in "Vrij Nederland", 2 July 1977 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Writings: Land Rover Club of Saudi Arabia, "The Sand Ladder:" submissions for newsletter, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Writings: Land Rover Club of Saudi Arabia, "The Sand Ladder," articles translated into Arabic, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Writings: "De Slag van al-Mu'tala: Orale literatuur als bron voor de geschiedenis van Saoedi-Arabie," in "Sharqiyyat" (Catholic University of Nijmegen), Year 3, Number 1, January 1991 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Writings: "Heartbeat: Conventionality and Originality in Najd Poetry," Asian Folklore Studies, vol. 52, pp. 33-74, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Writings: "Between ad-Dakhul and 'Afif: Oral Traditions of the 'Utaybah Tribe in Central Najd," Zeitschrift für arabische Linguistik, vol. 26, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Writings: Review of "The Arabian Oral Historical Narrative, an Ethnographic and Linguistic Analysis," by Saad Sowayan, in "Bibliotheca Orientalis, Vol. 51, No. 3/4, April-June 1994 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Writings: Review of "Politics in an Arabian Oasis: the Rashidi Tribal Dynasty," by Madawi al Rasheed, in "Bibliotheca Orientalis, Volume 51, No. 5/6, September-November 1994 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Writings: "'Wie Luidt de Doodsklok over de Arabieren?': Arabisme, Islam, en de Wereldbank."[published speech given at the University of Leiden], September 18, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Writings: "Poetry and Tribal Identity," in Proceedings of an International Conference on Middle Eastern Popular Culture, Magdalen College, Oxford, 17-21 September 2000 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Writings: "Praying Mantis in the Desert. The Najdi Poet Ibn Subayyil Consumed with Love for the Bedouin," in "Arabian Humanities," Issue 5, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Writings: "Charles Huber, voyageur en Arabie: sur deux manuscrits de poésie bédouine de la Bibliothèque nationale et universitaire de Strasbourg," in "La Revue de la BNU," No. 17, pp. 100-111, Spring 2018 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Writings: "Moskou bepaalt de speelruimte van Erdogan," in "NRC Handelsblad", 14 October 2019 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Writings: "De Pax Russica en de Primakov-Doctrine," in "Atlantisch Perspectief" (Den Haag), No. 1, 2020 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Research notes and background materials, 1974-2007, and undated
  - Articles: Fawasel (magazine), issue 39, "The Giant Poet: al-Dindān...", p, 98-99, August 1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Articles: Quṭūf (magazine), Dhū al-Qaʿdah, AH 1418, pp. 24-30, article profiling the poet al-Dindan, and Kurpershoek's study of his work, (February 1998) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Articles: Quṭūf (magazine), Dhū l-Ḥijjah, 1418, p. 52, contains article by Saad Sowayan, about Nabati poetry, [April 1998] (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Articles: Quṭūf (magazine), Muḥarram, 1419. Cover: "Al-Dindān: the Last Journey of the Last Bedouin," pp. 64-65, [May 1998] (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Articles: Quṭūf (magazine), Ṣafar 1419, p. 52, article "Elegy of al-Dindān," by Ibrāhīm ibn ʿAbd al-Raḥmān ibn Dhīb al-Wudʿānī, [June 1998] (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Baradouni, Abdullah: copied materials from Yemeni sources, 1993-1996, and undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography of popular (Nabati) poetry (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Calendar (from time of field work in Saudi Arabia), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Kitāb al-Ibil: photocopied of unattributed manuscript on camels, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Magazine: Turāth (Abu Dhabi: Emirates Cultural Club), issue 196; special issue on the occasion of the Sultan bin Zayed Heritage Festival, with cover story on camel racing, February 2016 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Nejd, general (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Netherlands, Consulate at Jeddah: copies of archival documents from 1926-1948 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Notes: exercises in translation and transliteration, from classical Arabic into Bedouin dialect (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Notes: topics, general (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Notes: themes in Bedouin poetry: plants and camels (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Notes: themes in Bedouin poetry: stars (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Notes: themes in Bedouin poetry: horses, palm trees, tents (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Notes: Arabic terms, drawn from other sources (Doughty, Hess, Musil), folder 1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Notes: Arabic terms, drawn from other sources (Doughty, Hess, Musil), folder 2 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Notes: Arabic terms, drawn from other sources (Doughty, Hess, Musil), folder 3 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Offprints: Bailey, Clinton. "The Ottomans and the bedouin tribes of the Negev," extract from "Ottoman Palestine, 1800-1914," edited by Gad G. Gilbar (Leiden: Brill), 1990 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Offprints: Bakalla, M.H.: two reviews of works about Arabic dialect and provers, of Mekka, from "Bulletin of the Faculty of Arts, University of Riyad," Vol. 3, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Offprints: Bonebakker, Seeger A. "Mubarrad's Version of Two Poems by Al-Khansā'," extract from "Festschrift Ewald Wagner zum 65. Geburstag, Band 2: Studien zur arabischen Dichtung" (Beirut and Stuttgart: Steiner), 1994 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Offprints: Bonebakker, Seeger A. "Sariqa and Formula: Three chapters from Ḥātimi's Ḥilyat al-Muḥādara," extract, from Annali dell'Istituto Universitario di Napoli, Vol. 46, No. 3 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Offprints: Bonebakker, Seeger A. "Some medieval views on fantastic stories," extract, inscribed by author, from Quaderni di Studi Arabi, 10, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Offprints: Brugman, J. "Muḥammad al-Sibāʻī and the Egyptian literary renaissance," extract from "Akten des VII. Kongresses fuer Arabistik und Islamwissenschaft" (Goettingen: Vandenhoeck und Ruprecht), 1974 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Offprints: de Jong, Frederick. "The Muslim Minorities in the Balkans on the Eve of the Collapse of Communism," extract, with inscription from author, from Islamic Studies (Islamabad: Islamic Research Institute), Vol. 36, No. 2, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Offprints: de Jong, Rudolf. "More Material on Fayyūmi Arabic (part 1)," extract from Zeitschrift fuer arabische Linguistik / Journal of Arabic Linguistics, Volume 31 (Wiesbaden: Harrassowitz), 1996 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Offprints: de Moor, Eduardus C.M., "Un Oiseau en Cage: le discours litteraire de Muḥammad Taymūr, 1892-1921" (Amsterdam: Editions Rodopi): booklet issued on awarding of doctorate to E.C.M. de Moor, Catholic University of Nijmegen, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Arabic Banqueters: Literature, Lexicography and Reality," extract from "Banquets d'Orient, Res Orientales IV, (Leuven: Peeters), 1992 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Arabic Debates of Jest and Earnest," extract from "Dispute Poems and Dialogues in the Ancient and Mediaeval Near East" (Orientalia Lovaniensia Analecta 42), 1991 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Arabic Poetics and Stylistics according to the Introduction of al-Durr al-Farīd by Muḥammad Ibn Aydamir (d. 710/1310)," extract from Zeitschrift der Deutschen Morgenlaendischen Gesellschaft," Band 146, Heft 2, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Mixtures of Jest and Earnest in Classical Arabic Literature, Part I," extract from Journal of Arabic Literature, Vol. 23, No. 2, July 1992 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Mixtures of Jest and Earnest in Classical Arabic Literature, Part II," extract from Journal of Arabic Literature, Vol. 23, No. 3, November 1992 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Musāwir al-Warrāq and the beginnings of Arabic gastronomic poetry," extract from Journal of Semitic Studies, Vol. 56, No. 2, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Pointed and Well-Rounded: Arabic Encomiastic and Elegiac Epigrams," extract from Orientalia Lovaniensia Periodica, Vol. 26, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Some Types of Ambiguity: a Poem by Abū Nuwās on Al-Fadl al-Raqāsī ," extract from Quaderni di Studi Arabi (Universita di Venezia), Number 10, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Street Arabs, Satire and the Status of Poetry," extract from "Proceedings of the 14th Congress of the Union Europeenne des Arabisants et Islamisants," (Budapest: The Arabist), [1988] (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Offprints: Gelder, Geert van. "Waspish Verses: Abū Nuwās's Lampoons on Zunbūr ibn Abī Ḥammād," extract from Annali di Ca' Foscari (Universita di Venezia), Vol. 35, No. 3, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Offprints: Holes, Clive. "The dispute of Coffee and Tea: a Debate-Poem from the Gulf," unidentified extract, later published in J.R. Smart, ed., "Tradition and Modernity in Arabic Language and Literature" (Surrey: Curzon Press), 1996 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Offprints: Ingham, Bruce. "Camel Terminology among the Al-Murrah Bedouins," extract from Zeitschrift fuer arabische Linguistik / Journal of Arabic Linguistics, Volume 22 (Wiesbaden: Harrassowitz), 1990 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Offprints: Kruk, Remke. "Back to the Boudoir: Arabic versions of the Sirat al-amir Ḥamza, warrior princesses, and the Sira's literary unity," in Amsterdamer Beitraege zu Aelteren Germanistik, Band 48, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Offprints: Kruk, Remke. "Ibn Abī l-Ash'ath's Kitāb al-Ḥayawān: a Scientific Approach to Anthropology, Dietetics and Zoological Systematics," extract from Zeitschrift fuer Geschichte der Arabisch-Islamischen Wissenschaften, Band 14, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Offprints: Skarżyńska-Bocheńska, Krystyna. "L'amour et la mort dans la poesie d'Adonis," extract from "Rocznik Orientalistyczny," Vol. 53, No. 1, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Offprints: Skarżyńska-Bocheńska, Krystyna. "La liberte et ses symboles dans l'oeuvre d'Adonis, 'Ali Ahmad Sa'id Isbir, poete arabe du Liban," extract from extract from "Proceedings of the 14th Congress of the Union Europeenne des Arabisants et Islamisants," (Budapest: The Arabist), [1988] (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Offprints: Skarżyńska-Bocheńska, Krystyna. "Le reflet de la loi morale d'honneur dans la litterature arabe contemporaine," extract from "Literaturen Asiens und Afrikas: Theoretische Probleme" (Berlin: Akademie-Verlag), 1981 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Offprints: Skarżyńska-Bocheńska, Krystyna. "Les traces de principes d'honneur des arabes de anteislam dans les coutumes et proverbes contemporaines," extract from "Proceedings of the Colloquium on Logos, Ethos, Mythos in the Middle East and North Africa," (Budapest: The Arabist, Budapest Studies in Arabic 18), undated, circa 1995 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Offprints: Somekh, Sasson. "Two Versions of Dialogue in Maḥmūd Taymūr's Drama," Princeton Near East Paper, Number 21, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Photocopy of review article: "On the Unity and Disunity of the Qaṣīdah" (reviews of work by Geert van Gelder and Sasson Somekh), in "Journal of Arabic Literature, Vol. XXIV, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Poetry: Shammar (1): photocopy of printed text, with handwritten annotations, after consultation with Shammar poets. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Poetry: Shammar (2): correspondence, photocopies of texts of transcriptions (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Poetry: Shammar (3): collected during research visit, not used in publication (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, copies of images from Snouck Hurgronje (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Project outline, for Saudi officials, undated, circa 1989 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Qusaybi, Ghani al-: open letter/poem to King, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Riyadh poetry conference: Newspaper clippings, February 1988 and undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Riyadh poetry conference: Papers by others: al-Bāza'ī, Sa'ad, "Hawl mafhum al-hadātha fī al-shi'r al-Khalījī...", 1988 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Riyadh poetry conference: Papers by others: al-Hāmid, 'Abd Allāh, "Al-tīyārāt al-shi'rīyah al-mu'āṣirah.... ", April 1988 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Riyadh poetry conference: Papers by others: Mahdi, Sami. [poetry compilation], 1988 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Riyadh poetry conference: Papers by others: al-Sarīḥī, Sa'ad, "Taḍārīs al-Khasūbah..." (Jeddah), [1988] (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Riyadh poetry conference: Papers by other: Sowayyan, Sa'ad, "Al-shi'r min al-mushāfihah ilá al-kitābah", [1988] (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Riyadh poetry conference: Papers by others: al-Wa'lhah, 'Abd al-Wahid, "Dawr al-tarjimah bil-shi'r al-hadīth", February 1988 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Riyadh poetry conference: Papers by others: unattributed essay about Shammar poetry, [1988] (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Shammar descendants in Turkey (Ahmed Sammaroglu): DVD of visit, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Shammar descendants in Turkey (Ahmed Sammaroglu): CDs of spoken poetry, recorded during Kurpershoek visit, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Ship's journal: from journey in Arabian Gulf, with copy of original text, English and Arabic translations, and notes. Copied from Dutch archive (unidentified, likely National Archives, The Hague). Tido Fredrik Van Kniphausen (captain) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Sources (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Trip notes: Sinai, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Trip notes: Hail, May 1988 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Trip notes: Hail, July 1988 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Trip notes: Empty Quarter, February 1989 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Trip notes: Nifi, July 1989 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Trip notes: field notebooks, "'Oteiba", 1989 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Trip notes: field notebooks, Saudi Arabia, September - December 1989 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Trip notes: field notebooks, Wadi Dawasir, September - December 1989 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Trip notes: field notebook, Wadi Dawasir, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Trip notes: journal of trip, Saudi Arabia and Oman, 20 March - 16 April 1994 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Trip notes: field notebook, Wadi Dawasir, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Wadi Dawasir: Background (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Wadi Dawasir: News clippings (1) (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Wadi Dawasir: News clippings (2) (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Wadi Dawasir: question of true Sheikh of Dawasir (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Dissertation and other academic materials, University of Leiden, 1970-1995
  - Bibliographies on Yūsuf Idrīs and works (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Biography of Yūsuf Idrīs: typescript (copy) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Dissertation: manuscript draft of text (1) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Dissertation: manuscript draft of text (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation: manuscript draft of text (3) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Dissertation: manuscript draft of text (4) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation: typescript draft segment (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Dissertation: Typescript draft, with corrections by Rowland Ellis (1) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Dissertation: Typescript draft, with corrections by Rowland Ellis (2) (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Dissertation: Typescript draft, with corrections by Rowland Ellis (3) (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Dissertation: Typescript draft, with corrections by Rowland Ellis (4) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Dissertation: Typescript draft, September 1980 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Dissertation: footnotes (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Dissertation: corrections to text (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Dissertation text: proofs of published version, July 1980 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Dissertation text: proofs of published version, October 1980 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation: interviews by Kurpershoek with Yūsuf Idrīs: notes and partial transcript, 1976-1978 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Dissertation: interviews by Kurpershoek with Yūsuf Idrīs: notes and questions, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation: interviews by Kurpershoek with Yūsuf Idrīs: summaries (Dutch) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Dissertation: interviews by Kurpershoek with Yūsuf Idrīs: transcripts (Arabic), 1978 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Dissertation: news clippings by and about Yūsuf Idrīs (1), 1976-1995 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Dissertation: news clippings by and about Yūsuf Idrīs (2), 1976-1995 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Dissertation: news clippings by and about Yūsuf Idrīs (3), 1976-1995 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Dissertation: news clippings by and about Yūsuf Idrīs (4), 1976-1995 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Dissertation: news clippings by and about Yūsuf Idrīs (5), 1976-1995 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Dissertation: notes, on notecards (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Dissertation: notes, general (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Dissertation: notes, as removed from binder (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation: notes, interviews of Yūsuf Idrīs by others (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Dissertation: notes, from review of Egyptian newspapers in Dār al Kutūb (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation: notes, from various sources (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Dissertation: quotations, selected (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Dissertation: Reprints and articles about Idris: Sāsson, Somekh, ["Literary studies of Yūsuf Idrīs (1): Qiṣṣat 'al-Nās' it's social meaning'], Al-Sharq, year 2, issue 6, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Dissertation: Reprints and articles about Idris: Sāsson, Somekh. ["Literary Studies of Yūsuf Idrīs (2): Movement and Rhythm in the story 'Mārsh al-ghurūb' (Sunset March),"], reprint of article from al-Sharq, year 2, issue 8, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Dissertation: Reprints and articles about Idrīs: Yūsuf Idrīs. "al-Barāʾah" (Innocence), in special issue on the short story, "al-Ādāb" (Literature) magazine, Beirut, issue 4, year 21, April 1973 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Dissertation: Reprints and articles about Idrīs: Special issue about Yūsuf Idrīs, "Adab wa-Naqd" magazine (Literature and Crticism), year 4, no. 34, Cairo, December 1987 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Masters thesis, University of Leiden: translation and textual analysis of "Al-Ta'īyāt al-ṣughrā" of 'Umar ibn al-Fāriḍ, 10 September 1973 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Other: Senior thesis, bachelors degree, University of Leiden: "'Al-Mu'ayyad', of Sheikh 'Alī Yūsuf," typescript text and footnotes, and manuscript draft, undated, circa 1971 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Other: Notes and diary, Cairo (during writing of senior thesis on Sheikh 'Alī Yūsuf, and al-Mu'ayyad), 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Other: notes, Cairo (research notes from sources at Dār al Kutūb), 1971 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Other: promotion to doctorate, University of Leiden, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Other: Dutch translation of "al Haram" by Yūsuf Idrīs, by P. M. Kurpershoek (1) (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Other: Dutch translation of "al Haram" by Yūsuf Idrīs, by P. M. Kurpershoek (2) (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Printed material: copied books and texts in Arabic and English
  - 'Abd āl-Rahman ibn Nāṣir. 'Unwān al Sa'd wa al Majd. [Resumes of the history of Saudi Arabia before the coming of the late Ibn Saud and his first half of His reign after the year 1936…] Folder 1 [undated] (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - 'Abd āl-Rahman ibn Nāṣir. 'Unwān al Sa'd wa al Majd. [Resumes of the history of Saudi Arabia before the coming of the late Ibn Saud and his first half of His reign after the year 1936…] Folder 2 [undated] (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Abu Hakima, Ahmad (editor). Kitāb lamʻ al-shihāb fī sīrat Muḥammad ibn ʻAbd al-Wahhāb (Beirut: Dār al-Thaqāfah|), [1967] (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Abū Mājid, 'Ali 'Abd āl Rahman, and 'Ali al Sālem al 'Abbād. Awwal khulṭah min al-shi'r al-qalṭah., Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - al-Aṣmaʿī, ʻAbd al-Malik ibn Qurayb. Kitāb al-Nabāt [book of plants]. Originally from AH 216, Cairo. Later edition of classic. Edited by Abdullah Yousef al Ghunaim., 1972 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - ʻAzzāwī, ʻAbbās. ʻAshāʼir al-ʻIrāq: v. 1. al-ʻAshaʼir al-qadīmah [Tribes of Iraq, vol. 1], (Baghdad: Matbaʻat Baghdād) part 1, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - ʻAzzāwī, ʻAbbās. ʻAshāʼir al-ʻIrāq: v. 1. al-ʻAshaʼir al-qadīmah [Tribes of Iraq, vol. 1], (Baghdad: Matbaʻat Baghdād), part 2, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - ʻAzzāwī, ʻAbbās. ʻAshāʼir al-ʻIrāq, v. 2. al-Kurdiyah [Tribes of Iraq: vol. 2, the Kurds] ( Baghdad: Matba'at al-Ma'arif), 1947 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - ʻAzzāwī, ʻAbbās. ʻAshāʼir al-ʻIrāq: Ahl al-Aryāf [Tribes of Iraq: the settled areas] (Baghdad:Sharikat al-tijarah wa-al-tiba'ah), vol. 3, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - ʻAzzāwī, ʻAbbās. ʻAshāʼir al-ʻIrāq: Ahl al-Aryāf [Tribes of Iraq: the settled areas], (Baghdad: Sharikat al-tijarah wa-al-tiba'ah), vol. 4, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Batanūnī, Muḥammad Labīb. al-Riḥlāh al-Ḥijāzīyah. [Journey to Hejaz]. ( [Cairo]: Maṭbaʻat al-Jamalīyah), A.H .1329 (1911 C.E.) (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - al Bilādī, 'Atiq ibn Ghayth. Nasab Ḥarb :qabīlat Ḥarb, ansābuhā, furūʻuhā, tārīkhuhā wa-diyāruhā [Genealogy of Ḥarb tribe]. 3rd edition. (Makkah: Dār Makkah), 1984 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Dimyāṭī, Maḥmūd Muṣṭafá. Muʻjam asmāʼ al-nabātāt al-wāridah fī Tāj al-ʻarūs lil-Zabīdī [Dictionary of names of plants from "Tāj al-ʿĀrūs"]. [Cairo]: al-Dār al-Miṣrīyah lil-Taʼlīf wa-al-Tarjamah, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Fākhirī, Muḥammad ibn ʻUmar. al-Akhbār al-Najdīyah [Report on the Nejd]. (Saudi Arabia: no publisher identified). Edited by ʻAbd Allāh ibn Yūsuf Shibl., undated, circa 1980s (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Fardūs, Fahd Muḥammad. Dīwān Ibn Fardūs (Kuwait: the author), 1976 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - al-Ḥamdān, Muḥamed ibn 'Abdāllah. Fahras maktabah. (Riyadh: Gais Bookshop), A.H. 1432 (2011 C.E.) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Ḥamza, Fuʼād. Qalb Jazīrat al-ʻArab [Heart of the Arabian Peninsula]. ([Makka]: al-Maktaba al-Salafiyya), part 1, 1933 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Ḥamza, Fuʼād. Qalb Jazīrat al-ʻArab [Heart of the Arabian Peninsula]. ([Makka]: al-Maktaba al-Salafiyya), part 2, 1933 (Box 22, Folder 5)